songfacts.com 2017-06-06

# Songfacts Privacy Policy and Legal Notice : Songfacts Pages

This website is maintained by Songfacts, LLC, of Canton, Connecticut. No part of the site may be reproduced without written permission from  
Songfacts, LLC. For more on who we are and how the site works, please see the [SongFAQ](http://www.songfacts.com/blog/pages/about_us/).

All information on this site is the copyright of Songfacts, LLC.

We are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our website. It does not apply to information that you may submit to us offline, or to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

By visiting our Website, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of our Website and our affiliate sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy retroactively, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don't see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at [feedback@songfacts.com](mailto:feedback@songfacts.com). 

**What Information Is Collected and Stored?**

We don't sell, barter, give away, or rent your personal information to any outside company. We like you, but there's only so much we want to know about you: For purposes of registration, we collect some identifiable information such as your first name, email address, and location. We also may collect your browser type, domain name, access times and referring websites addresses.

**Do I Have To Register?**

No. We only ask you to register for things like posting comments or adding songfacts - stuff where we need to know a little bit about you, often to credit your contributions.

**Anonymous Information**

In addition, when you interact with the Website, our servers may keep an activity log that does not identify you individually ("Anonymous Information"). Generally, this information is collected though "traffic data". We collect and store certain administrative and traffic information including: source IP address, time of access, date of access, web page(s), software crash reports and type of browser used.

**Use of Cookies and Spyware**

We never use or install spyware on your computer, nor do we use spyware to retrieve information from your computer.

Also, like many Websites, we use "cookies", which are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences. We only use cookies if you are signing in and choose to select the "remember me" box, which allows you to stay logged in (cookies are necessary in this case).

You may occasionally get cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this cookie policy.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Like some Websites, we may use web beacons. A web beacon is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about your use of a given website. Like cookies, web beacons allow Songfacts and its technology providers to summarize overall usage patterns for our analysis and provide personalized services. We do not share or provide personally identifiable information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers with our advertisers without your express permission.

We work with third-party advertising companies on this Website. These companies may use information about your visits to this Website (not including your name, address, or other personally identifiable information) to provide advertisements on this Website, other websites and other media about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about these practices and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

If you are located in Europe, some of the data that we process may be protected by data protection laws such as, in the United Kingdom, the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”). Under the Act, you have certain rights to request information about, get access to or request the amendment of any such personal data. If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us at feedback@songfacts.com. See the UK Information Commissioner's Office website at http://www.ico.gov.uk for further details. 

**Use of the Site**

Use of Songfacts is governed by our [Terms of Service](http://www.songfacts.com/blog/pages/terms_of_service/).

**Children's Privacy**

We also do not collect or maintain personal information from those users who we actually know are under 13. Should we learn or be notified that we have collected information from users under the age of 13, we will immediately delete such personal information.

**How We Use Your Information?**

Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not use or disclose information about your individual visits to our Website or your Personal Information collected online to any companies not affiliated with us. 

**Use of Anonymous Information**

We use Anonymous Information to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and who our users are so we can improve our Website and ensure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many people as possible. We also use Anonymous Information to provide statistical "ratings" information in aggregated form to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use Website. We may also use or share Anonymous Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary.

**Transactional partners**

We may share non-personal information with our partners and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this Website during a specific time period. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

**What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?**

Personal Information collected by our Website is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. 

**What Happens When I Link To or From Another Web Site?**

This Website may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of Songfacts or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. These other sites may also send their own cookies to you, collect your data or solicit your Personal Information. Always be aware of where you end up. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other Websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave this Website and read the privacy policies of each and every Website that you visit.

**Google Analytics**

To get anonymous demographic data so we can better understand the interests of our audience, we have implemented the Google analytics demographics and interest reporting features. This allows us to review anonymous data about age, gender and interests of visitors. This information is collected through your Google ad settings, and not in a format that is personally-identifiable by us. This means we cannot identify what information is about you, and we will make no effort to find out. You can [opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings. In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics.

**Public Areas, Message Boards**

Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as message boards or comments, becomes public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose and do not post any Personal Information that you expect to keep private.
